A Guide to the Audrey Emmons Architectural Collection, 1974-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Audrey Emmons Architectural Collection, 1974-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1997-018
1.5 cu. ft. 3 boxes; 1 oversize folder
The Audrey Emmons collection consists of architectural drawings, photographs and slides, and job files of designs Emmons did in San Francisco, Sausalito, and other Northern California locations from the mid-1970s until 1996.
Emmons, Audrey
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Audrey Emmons Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in 1997.
Biographical Information
Audrey Emmons was born Audrey Jean Durland on November 4, 1921, in Manhattan, Kansas. She received her B.S. in Architecture degree from Kansas State University in 1943. She served as a Junior Naval Architect at the Department of the Navy in Washington, D.C., from 1943 to 1944, and as a draftsperson with the firms of William Smull, AIA, in Washington, D.C., from 1948 to 1949, and Bechtel Corporation in San Francisco, California, from 1949 to 1950.
Emmons was an architect with several firms in San Francisco, including Wurster, Bernardi & Emmons AIA, from 1950 to 1955, and Malone & Hooper, AIA, from 1955 to 1963. In 1964 she became a partner with Hooper Olmsted & Emmons, AIA, (1964-1977) and Hooper, Olmsted Emmons Hrovat, AIA, (1977-1980). She established her own practice in 1980. In 1961 she married architect Donn Emmons.
Emmons served in many capacities on several committees and task forces in the San Francisco Chapter of the American Institute of Architects and the California Council AIA. She was a member of the City of Sausalito Community Appearances Advisory Board (1971-1974) and the Architectural Selection Board of the State Colleges of California (1977-1980), among other prominent civic and professional committees.
Emmons, a licensed architect of California and the District of Columbia, was elected to the College of Fellows of the AIA in 1984. In 1983 she received a Distinguished Service Award from the College of Architecture and Design of Kansas State University. She died April 1, 1997, in Sausalito, California.
Scope and Content
The Audrey Emmons collection consists of architectural drawings, photographs and slides, and job files of designs Emmons did in San Francisco, Sausalito, and other Northern California locations from the mid-1970s until 1996. The collection also includes biographical information about Emmons and the medal she earned in 1984 when she achieved fellowship in the AIA.
Arrangement
This collection is divided into two series Professional Papers and Project Records. The materials are then arranged chronologically within each series.
Index Terms
Subjects:
International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Contents List
- Professional Papers,1978-1997
  - Applications for Fellowship in American Institute of Architects (Folder 1 of 2),1978-1984 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Applications for Fellowship in American Institute of Architects (Folder 2 of 2),1978-1984 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Photographs of Emmons at work-Mill Valley, California,1980 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - SPCA booklet, San Francisco, California,1982 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Fellowship metal, 1984 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Article on fellowship induction into the American Institute of Architects,1984 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Induction into the College of Fellows of the AIA,1984 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Biographical information about Emmons,1997 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Project Records,1974-1996
  - Low cost student housing-photographs and negatives, Sonoma Grove, California,1974. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Restoration and remodeling of a pair of flats - Awards Presentation, San Francisco, California, 1981. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Ludwig house, San Francisco, California, 1981-1993
    - Kitchen, bedroom, laundry remodel, San Francisco, California,1981 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Contract and paperwork, San Francisco, California,1982 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Remodeling of Ludwig house, San Francisco, California,1982-1984 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Bath, bookcase, and fireplace, San Francisco, California,1986 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Bomb shelter and kitchen lighting, San Francisco, California,1993 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Ludwig house, Woodside, California,1983-1995
    - Plans for Ludwig poolhouse pavilion, Woodside, California (6 drawings),1983 (Oversize 1)
    - Poolhouse pavilion plans,Woodside, California, 1983 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Specifications and consulting information for poolhouse pavilion, Woodside, California,1983 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Photographs and slides of Ludwig poolhouse pavilion, Woodside, California, 1984 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Ludwig poolhouse pavilion awards presentation, Woodside, California, 1985 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Photographs of Ludwig house,Woodside, California, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Research and remodeling plans for Ludwig house, Woodside, California, 1987 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Specifications for Ludwig poolhouse pavilion, Woodside, California, 1987 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Remodeling for Ludwig house, Woodside, California, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Remodeling for Ludwig house, Woodside, California (3 drawings),1989-1995 (Oversize 1)
    - Bedroom cabinets for Ludwig house, Woodside, California, 1990 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Photographs of Ludwig house, Woodside, California, 1990 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - 410 Johnson St., Photographs, Sausalito, California,1985 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Sausalito, California, Noteworthy structures and sites, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Ludwig house, Stinson Beach, California, 1988
    - Photographs and paperwork, 1988 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Designs and tracings for Ludwig house, Stinson Beach, California, 1988 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Specifications for Ludwig house, Stinson Beach, California, 1988 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Plans for Ludwig house, Stinson Beach, California (10 drawings), 1988 (Oversize 1)
  - Todd house, Stinson Beach, California, 1990-1991
    - Specifications, 1990 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Plans for Todd house, Stinson Beach, California, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - David Todd house, Stinson Beach, California, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Plans for Todd house, Stinson Beach, California (9 drawings), 1990-1991 (Oversize 1)
  - Seadrift vacation house awards presentation, Stinson Beach, California, 1992 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Broom house, Sausalito, California, 1993-1996
    - Specifications, 1993 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Photographs, paperwork, and designs, Broom house, Sausalito, California, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Remodeling, deck, kitchen doors, and bath, Broom house, Sausalito, California, 1996 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Bath, closet and landscaping for Broom house, Sausalito, California, 1996 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Plans for house and garage, Broom house, Sausalito, California (5 drawings), 1993 (Oversize 1)
  - Mechanics Institute library interior, location unknown, 1994 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Susan Frank, Photographs of remodeling, Palo Alto, California, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Slides of miscellaneous projects (Folder 1 of 2), n.d. (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Slides of miscellaneous projects (Folder 2 of 2), n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Rodney Johnson house, Photographs, Wolfback Ridge, Marin County, California, n.d. (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Guide Dogs for the Blind Inc., New Kennel, San Rafael, California, n.d. (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Chapman house, Photographs, Sausalito, California, n.d. (Box-folder 3:13)